Uh hello. I'm here today with Shan Lee,
co-founder of DB Boss. Welcome.
>> Hi. Nice to meet everyone. And we're
going to talk about durable execution
and deboss. So, Pedria just released an
integration with Deboss that makes AI
agents reliable by default. So, let's
flash. Uh, Shen, what is DBOS?
>> Yeah. So, Deboss is a lightweight
durable execution library that is built
on top of Postgress. So, you can use it
directly in your existing applications
without rearchitecting your code.
And um what are the benefits of using
deboss over any other durable execution
solutions in the market right now?
>> Yeah. So I think the main benefit of
deboss is that it's really lightweight.
Uh often the time people come to us
saying they can integrate deboss
seamlessly into their applications
because they are already using a
Postgress database and they just need to
add a few Python decorators to their
functions and then their uh their
applications become durable. So they
don't need to host a separate
orchestration server and they don't need
to host dedicated workers for that.
Hence lightweight.
>> Yes. So it's very similar to the
philosophy of panic AI where it's also a
very lightweight and flexible library.
>> Yes. Yes indeed. Very good. Um so since
we we started talking about pentic AI
then so penti lets you express agent
logic and tools and structured outputs
without introducing a separate agent
runtime.
Um can you explain to me what are the
benefits of using deboss for
reliability?
>> Yeah. So by using deboss together uh
with padic AI uh you can we can
automatically checkpoint the the output
of the progress of your workflows your
agenic workflows. For example every time
you call an external service we'll
checkpoint a result and every time you
call the external tool we can checkpoint
the result of that too. So that if your
server crashes or something happened in
the middle or you redeploy your
applications, you don't have to restart
from the very beginning. So you can save
the amount of tokens you burned on those
requests and you can save a lot of time
uh instead of because instead of running
from the very beginning, you continue
from where you left off using the
checkpoint.
>> That sounds like a very useful thing for
deep research agents. So actually I can
show you the code for like a fun uh deep
research agent uh I built with panic AI
and deboss.
So we published this demo under deboss
demo apps python panic research agent.
So the setup is really easy. You install
UV you set up your uh API keys for panic
AI gateway. You set up logfire and
deboss conductor. And then the main
logic is just in one single file.
So you just need to define three agents.
Uh this the first is a planning agent.
It basically analyzes the query and
designs a plan for deep research uh to
answer the query. And then we'll use the
search agent to search the web and find
related results. And finally we'll use
an analysis agent to aggregate results
uh and then provide a final report. So
as you can see, Pyenic AI makes it
really simple to define those agents
using different models, using different
prompts and because thanks to structured
output, you will get a very clean report
uh and a very clean uh agent
interactions across different agents.
And then once you define those agents,
you can simply wrap those agents as
deboss agents. just one line you you
define your agent using pyen AI and then
you use the py deboss integration called
a deboss agent now you have a durable
agent and then what's more when you
actually want to call the agents instead
of calling the original agent you call
the deboss agent and for sub aent
calling it's even simpler so we define
an extra search tool on this analysis
agent by calling the deboss search
agent. So this uh analysis agent will do
a sub aent call and then everything is
recorded through deboss. So even sub
aents can be traced and checkpointed
correctly to the database. So you will
never lose progress. And finally this is
the main deep research workflow. So we
can see that we first use the plan agent
to get results and then for each plan
step we use deba start workflow async.
So we can search we can start those
search workflows in parallel so we can
fan out to parallel workflows and then
at after that we can collect results
later on so that you get the benefit of
concurrency and parallelism. So it
increases the speed of processing and
finally once we collect all the
information we'll put it to the deboss
analysis agent and then finally we get
the result. So everything every step
every model calling will be recorded in
the database. So you can crash anywhere
in between and your agent will come back
right online.
Very cool. Are you going to run this
example for SD today? Sure. Uh so before
running that um we can talk about the
logfire integration. So in this demo if
it detects a logfire token it will just
configure logfire and then instrument
pinic AI. And the benefit is that so
deboss automatically generate traces.
you just need to point the trace to uh
you just need to enable the trace in the
deboss config. So once you enable the
trace uh deboss will automatically
export everything to lock file.
Okay. So what about if I want to
configure my spans using DOS? Is it is
that possible?
Uh so for the spans in your agent tools
so like if you have any specific tools
you want to create a special span then
you can just use span here directly. Do
you want to see the demo now? Yes
please. Cool. So we actually built a
front end. It's uh built with TypeScript
but you can see if we just have the
front end uh it doesn't run anything
because we don't have the back end. And
so let's get started to run the back
end. So we simply need to uv run python
main.py. Just run that python file.
It will load up and you can see I've run
some queries before because everything
is stored in the database. When it
starts up, it will just load whatever is
stored there before.
>> So what is the what's this interesting
question there? Find me a list of
Python AI conferences in 26.
Let's go. So you can see in this demo uh
there are three stages for this agent.
The first stage is planning. So it will
call the planning agent. It's running.
>> Very good.
>> And then we start five concurrent search
workflows. By the way, you will be able
to find see all the workflows on the
deboss console. You can see all the
console there. Five workflows running in
parallel. And then we can kill the
agent. I would like to see that on log
fire too. Oh, sure. So, let's see. So,
those are the traced agent run on
lockfire for now. But I stopped agent.
So currently it got stuck in analysis
agent.
>> So let's just restart it
and you'll see it comes all back online
and instead of repeating this all the
search agents it directly jumps to the
analysis agents and continue the
workflows.
You can see the workflow details here
and analysis agent is still running in
progress and on logfire you will see it
continues with the analysis agent
and you can see on the this side it
didn't go through all the planning and
search phase it's continues with anal
analyzing phase has finished completed
and we'll see comprehensive report
and very nice yep I I guess it skipped
the PI AI conference. It should
>> not there. I don't like this.
>> So sometimes you might want to restart
the workflow. Maybe you want to
um
for example you want to fork the
workflow and run it again. So we'll keep
running.
We able to see it?
Oh, we're able to fork the workflow
through deboss. So instead of going to a
planning agent, we fork from the
searching step. So now we're re we're
searching it again
and now analyzing it again and hopefully
we'll get some better results for this
time. Fingers crossed. But I was when we
fart um we fart just from the search. Uh
so we're not rerunning the entire
workflow. We're just rerunning the
section um that we're interested on.
Yes, exactly. So when we fork a
workflow, we'll keep the checkpoints
from the previous one up to a certain
point and then we'll kind of explore an
alternative path from there.
So hopefully this time we'll get some
new results.
>> Absolutely. And we can continue to
uh monitor the cost and everything.
>> Blockfire
>> still running.
>> It's cost something two cents. Now it's
done.
>> And now it's done indeed.
>> Whoa.
>> 10 cents.
>> 10 cent.
>> Still no P AI com, but it's okay. I
accepted.
>> Okay.
I'm sure in the previous run I actually
searched PI AI
so it's not really stable. Sometimes
when you asked the agents the same
question they will give you different
results. So I think the benefit of using
deboss is also using deboss and uh panic
is that you can explore different
options. You can observe what happened
in the past and then you can do more
auditing on what agents have done and
how the decisions were made based on the
previous output based on certain like
basically you can get the context for
your agent runs
>> and running sections as well which is
quite important if you're trying to
debug and understand in which section of
my AI workflow is the hallucination
happening um or any other bias.
Wonderful. So for more information, we
have a gist with this code. We also have
a blog post which with much more detail
of everything that we just talked about.
And if anybody wants to keep in contact
with you or learn more about deboss
where they should go,
uh visit our website at dbos.dev.
And uh you can also read the uh deboss
integration docs on the panic AI uh docs
page. Uh yeah, feel free to reach out
and we're always here to answer
questions and help you with uh reliable
agents.
>> Wonderful. Thank you so much. This is
very good. Thank you. Um and that's it.
Well, AI stateless engineering. Thank
you.